Knock Down the House is a documentary film directed by Rachel Lears.
In 2018, a young bartender in the Bronx, a coal miner’s daughter in West Virginia, a grieving mother in Nevada and a
registered nurse in Missouri join a movement of insurgent candidates challenging powerful incumbents in Congress.
Without political experience or corporate money, these four women
are attempting to do what many consider impossible.
Self, played by Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez.
Self, played by Cori Bush.
Self, played by Paula Jean Swearingen.
Self, played by Amy Vilela.
Self, played by Joe Crowley.
Self, played by Ilhan Omar.
Knock Down the House is a 2019 American
documentary film directed by Rachel Lears.
It revolves around the 2018 congressional primary campaigns of Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, Amy Vilela, Cori Bush and Paula Jean Swearengin,
four progressive Democrats endorsed by Justice Democrats and Brand New Congress who ran in that year's midterm elections.
The film had its world premiere at the 2019 Sundance
Film Festival on January 27, 2019.
It was released on May 1, 2019, by Netflix and received acclaim from critics.
The film explores themes of underdog, election campaign, u.s.
congress, female politician, political candidate.